Standardize Success Factors
Welcome back to this session on value creation.
Now, we come in to the last phase called attenuate gaps.
And that consists of two stages, two steps,
standardize success factors and integrate lessons learned.
Right now, we’re going to look at standardizing on success factors.
And as before, we’re going to blow this out so that we can more closely examine
what we mean by standardizing on our success factors.
I’m going to abbreviate it here,
standardize success factors.
Now, what I want to do is to sit back
and think about all that I've went through. What made me successful in that attempt?
Or look at the failures, and say what would've kept the failure from occurring?
That's another way of finding a success factor.
But I want to find those factors. Those things that I did. See.
The things that I do, but in the past tense.
The things that I did, that cause success to happen.
As I look across the process of what I've went through,
from recognizing value needs; to defining the change opportunities;
to measuring the existing conditions. I did a lot of things in there,
some of which worked and some didn't.
Nonetheless, I gotta identify which ones were successful. That's what we’re talking about.
Those things that I did. Those factors that caused success to happen. See.
Y is a function of X. Success is a function of those factors.
So, I want to go back and review. Identify the key factors of doing
the things that I did that caused success to occur.
And then I want to standardize on them. Big word. What does that mean? Standardize.
That means, you know, like a standardized test. It doesn't change. It’s consistent over time.
It's a standard way of getting the work done.
That's another way of looking at it. It's a standard way of getting the work done.
It’s the way, I do business. It's the way I conduct my life.
It's the way we run the business. See standardized way.
So, what I want to do is think about the things I did that created success
and standardize on them. Make them repeatable.
So, I can keep success flowing in the future. So, I can keep the value increasing.
So that I can keep creating more value with less effort.
That's what standardization does for me. It allows me to keep repeating my successes.
Standardization also allows me to generalize my success factors.
For example, we may have solved the problem of our job.
We got the dog taken care of. We circumvented the dog.
I made myself robust to the dog by changing the time I went to get the newspaper.
I’ve become impervious to the effects of my neighbor’s dog.
I was Designing for Six Sigma.
Keyword there. By making myself robust to the neighbor’s dog. By finding a new time
to allow that opportunity to happen. Now, I think about that. I look at what I did there.
So, I standardize on that and I try to generalize that to other situations.
So, what I mean by that is this. Here is a success factor.
And, I’ll call it X, whatever success factor X may be.
And here’s different situations in my life. Situation A. Situation B. Situation C.
Different situations in my life. And this happened to be the one with the dog.
So, with my job and the dog. So, I generalize  that and standardize on success factors.
Then, I generalize it to other situations in my life.
I try to make it applicable. The principles of that success factor.
In other situations in my life. That saves me from going through things again.
It tends to make success come automatic. Huh!
Maybe that's what people say, gee, you're lucky.
Maybe luck is the intersect between
preparedness and opportunity.
Being prepared and opportunity.
I always said that, luck is the wreck
between the automobile of opportunity and the bus of preparedness.
That's a wreck. That's a good wreck. Happens right there.
When those things intersect. Boom, in most people's eyes, you're lucky.
Well, no I'm not lucky.
I design my destiny. I didn't let others design the destiny for me.
I went through recognize my value needs.
Defined the things that I got a change to realize those values.
And then I measured my existing conditions. I assessed them.
And then I analyzed the forces that put those conditions in place.
And then I found new action settings for those.
And I minimized the variation around it, so I could be more consistent.
I looked across that whole thing, and defined the success factors that I needed
to repeat, to cause that, and I generalized that to other situations in my life.
That's what we call Six Sigma in your personal life.
That's how you get breakthrough in your personal life.
That's how you create value in your personal life.
That's why standardizing on success factors is so important.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.